The following content is provided under a Creative
Commons license.
Your support will help MIT OpenCourseWare continue to
offer high quality educational resources for free.
To make a donation or view additional materials from
hundreds of MIT courses, visit MIT OpenCourseWare at
ocw.mit.edu.
All right, let's get started everyone.
So good afternoon.
Welcome to the second lecture of 6.0001.
And also of 600.
So as always, if you'd like to follow along with the
lecture, with the lectures, please go ahead and
download the slides and the code that I'll provide at
least an hour before class every day.
All right, so quick recap of what we did last time.
So last time we talked a little bit about what a
computer is.
And I think the main takeaway from the last lecture is
really that a computer only does what it is told.
So it's not going to spontaneously make
decisions on its own.
You, as the programmer, have to tell it what you want it to
do by writing programs.
OK, so we talked about simple objects, and these
objects were of different types.
So we saw integers, floats, and booleans.
And then we did a couple of simple operations with them.
Today, we're going to look at a different, a new type of
object called a string.
And then we're going to introduce some more powerful
things in our programming toolbox.
So we're going to look at how to branch within a program and
how to make the computer repeat certain tasks
within our program.
All right, so let's begin by looking at strings.
So strings are a new object type.
We've seen so far integers, which were whole
numbers, floats, which were decimal numbers.
And we've seen booleans which were true and false.
So strings are going to be sequences of characters.
And these characters can be anything.
They could be letters, digits, special characters, and
also spaces.
And you tell Python that you're talking about a string
object by enclosing it in quotation marks.
So in this case, I'm creating an object whose value is
H-E-L-L-O space, T-H-E-R-E.
And Python knows it's a string object because we're enclosing
it in quotations.
They could be either double quotes or single quotes, but
as long as you're consistent, it doesn't matter.
And this object, we're binding it to this variable
named high.
And we're using that using the equal sign, which is the
assignment operator.
OK, so from now on, whenever we refer to this
variable high, Python's going to say, oh, I know what
the value is, and it's that string of characters.
So we're going to learn about two things that you can do on
strings today, two operations.
One is to concatenate them.
And concatenation is really just a fancy word for using
this plus operator, which means put the strings
together.
So I have this original variable named high.
And I create a new variable called name.
And in it, I'm going to assign the string
ANA to the variable name.
And when I use the plus operator in between high and name,
those two variables, Python's going to look at the values
of those two, and it's going to just put them together.
I'm going to switch to spider.
And this is just that example from the slides.
So let's see what happens.
So I have the variable high.
The variable name.
And I'm just concatenating those two together.
And then I'm going to print that out.
So if I run the code, notice it prints out hello there, Anna.
There's no space.
And there's no space because the concatenation operator,
the plus, doesn't add any spaces implicitly.
So again, another example of just doing what it's told.
If we want to add a space, we'd have to actually insert
the space manually.
So that's this line here, line eight.
And in this line, we're concatenating the value
of the variable high with a space.
Notice we're putting it in quotation marks, just a space.
And then with name.
So if we go ahead and print that value,
notice this was that garbage greeting there.
And now we have a proper greeting.
So that's the concatenation between strings.
And then the other thing we're going to look at related
to strings is the star operator.
So that's this one here on line 10.
So Python allows you to use the star operator, which is
stands for multiplication, between a string and a number.
And when you do that, Python interprets it
as repeat that string that many number of times.
So in this case, I'm creating a silly greeting.
And I'm concatenating the value of high, which is hello there,
with the space plus the name.
So notice here I'm using parentheses to tell Python
do this operation first.
And then multiply whatever the result of this is by three.
So if I print that out, it's going to multiply the space
with my name three times.
And it's going to concatenate that with hello there.
So that's exactly what it printed out there.
Last lecture, we talked a little bit about print.
Today I'm going to talk about some nuances related to print.
So you use print to interact with the user.
It's cool to write programs that print things out to the user.
So the keyword here being print.
And then you put parentheses after print.
And in the parentheses, you put in whatever you want to show
the user.
So in this little program, I create a variable named x.
I assign it the value one.
And then I print one.
Here I'm casting.
So I'm taking the number one, the integer one,
and I'm casting it to a string.
And you'll see why in a moment.
So I want to bring to your attention a couple things here.
So in the first print, I'm using commas everywhere here.
And in the second print, I'm using plus.
So by definition, you can use commas inside the parentheses
of print.
And if you use a comma, Python's going to automatically
add a space in between the two things
that the comma is in between, the values.
So my fav num is the first thing.
And the second thing is whatever is after the comma.
Let's take x.
So if you use a comma, Python's going to automatically
insert a space for you.
Sometimes you might want that.
Sometimes you might not.
If you don't want that, you can use the concatenation
operation, the plus.
And you can add all of your little bits together
to create one big string.
If you're using commas, the objects in between the commas
do not all have to be strings.
That's the plus side of using commas.
But the downside is you get spaces everywhere.
If you use plus operator, the plus side
is Python does exactly what you tell it to do.
But everything has to be a string object.
So my fav num is a string object.
You have to convert all of your numbers to string objects
and so on.
So if we look at spider, this is almost the same code.
So here I don't have spaces anywhere.
So you can see that the first line here
has commas everywhere.
So I'm going to have spaces in between every one of the things
that I'm printing out.
This line here is sort of a combination
between commas and concatenation.
So depending on where I use the comma,
I'm going to have an extra space.
And this line here just has concatenation everywhere.
So if I run this, notice this very first line
added spaces everywhere in between all my objects.
The second one added spaces somewhere.
And you can sort of trace through and see exactly where
the spaces were added.
And the last line here didn't add spaces anywhere.
So printing things out to the console is nice.
But the second part of writing an interactive program
is getting input from the user.
And that's a more interesting part.
So if you've done problem set zero,
you might have sort of already tried
to understand this on your own.
But here we are.
So the way you get input from the user
is using this command function called input.
And inside the parentheses,
you type in whatever you'd like to prompt the user with.
So in this case, in my example here,
I have input and then here I said type anything.
So the user is going to see this text here.
And then the program is just going to stop.
And it's going to wait for the user to type in something
and hit Enter.
As soon as the user types in Enter,
whatever the user types in becomes a string.
If the user types in a number, for example,
that becomes the string, that number.
So everything the user types in
is going to be made as a string.
In this line right here,
whatever the user types in becomes a string.
And we're going to bind that string object
to this variable named called text.
So now further in my program,
I could do whatever I want with this variable text.
In this case, I'm going to print five star text.
So if the user, for example, gave me ha,
I'm going to print ha five times.
If the user gave me five,
what do you think the user's,
what do you think's going to be printed out?
25 or five, five times?
Great, yes, exactly, five, five times.
Oftentimes, you don't want to work with numbers as strings.
You want to work with numbers as numbers.
So you have to cast.
And we learned that last lecture.
You cast by just putting in this little bit
right in front of the input.
And you can cast it to whatever type you want.
Here, I cast it to an int,
but you can also cast to a float.
If you want to work with floats.
And that converts whatever the user typed in,
as long as it's some number that Python knows
how to convert into the number itself.
So in this case, if the user gives me five,
I'm going to print out five times five,
instead of five, five times.
So that's the code here.
So the first bit is I'm going to get the user
to type in anything,
and I'm going to put five, five, five.
And then when I type in the number,
since I'm casting it,
I'm going to do operations with the number.
Yeah, question.
Why do you want to cast to?
Oh, the question is why do you want to cast to a string?
Why do you want to cast a string to a number?
Oh, so Python always, whatever you type in,
just by default, by definition of the input command,
Python always makes it a string.
So if you want to work with numbers,
you have to explicitly tell it,
I'm going to work with a number.
So even if you give it the number five,
it's going to think it's the string five.
Yeah, that's just how input works.
The next thing we're going to look at
is ways that you can start adding tests in your code.
And before you can start adding tests,
before you can start adding tests in your code,
you need to be able to do the actual tests.
So this is where comparison operators come in.
So here, let's assume that INJ are variables.
The following comparisons are going to give you a boolean.
So it's either going to say this is true or this is false.
So that's going to be your test.
So if INJ are variables,
you're allowed to compare ints with ints,
floats with floats, strings with strings,
and you're allowed to compare ints and floats
between themselves, but you're not allowed
to compare a string with a number.
In fact, if you even try to do that in Python,
in spite here, if I try to say,
is the letter A greater than five?
I get some angry text right here.
And this just tells me,
Python doesn't understand the meaning
of how do I compare a string with a number, right?
So just like in math, we can do these usual comparisons.
We can say if something's greater than something,
greater or equal to, less than less than or equal to.
I'd like to bring to your attention the equality.
So the single equal sign is an assignment.
So you're taking a value and you're signing it to a variable,
but when you're doing the double equal sign,
this is the test for equality.
Is the value of variable i the same
as the value of the variable j?
And that's, again, also going to give you a Boolean,
either true or false.
And you can also test for inequality
with the exclamation equal.
So that means, is the value of the variable i
not equal to the value of the variable j?
True if, yes, false if, no.
So those are comparison operators
on integer, floats, and strings.
On Booleans, you can do some logic operators.
And the simplest is just inverting.
So if a is a variable that has a Boolean value,
not a is just going to invert it.
So if a is true, then not a is false and vice versa.
This is a table that sort of represents what I've said here
so you can do, you can use and and or.
These are keywords in Python.
You can use those two keywords on Boolean variables.
And you get the result a and b is only true
if both a and b are true.
And a or b is only false if a and b are false.
And this is the complete table,
just in case you need to reference it.
All right, so now that we have ways
to do logical test, yep, question right there.
Yeah, great question.
So what does it mean to compare a string
with a string with a greater than?
So that's just going to compare them lexicographically.
So does it come first in the alphabet?
So we can even test that out.
We can say is a greater than b and it's false.
So b becomes later in the alphabet than a.
Okay, so now we have ways to do the tests.
So we can add some branching
to our programming toolbox now
that we have ways to do tests.
This is a map of MIT.
I'm going to go through sort of a little example
to motivate why we want to do branching in our code.
And I think after this lecture
you'll be able to sort of code up this algorithm
that I'm going to explain.
So most of us see MIT as a maze.
I first did when I came here.
When I first came here obviously
I signed up for the free food mailing list.
And MIT being a maze I had no idea where to go, right?
What the shortest path was to free food.
So one way to think about it is all I wanted to do
was get to the free food.
A very simple algorithm to get there
would be to say, okay, I'm going to take my right hand
and I'm going to make sure that my right hand
is always on a wall, okay?
And I'm going to go around campus
with my right hand always being at a wall
and eventually I'll get to where the free food is.
There might not be any left, right?
But I'll be there, okay.
So the algorithm is as follows, okay?
If my right hand always has to be on a wall
then I'm going to say if there's no wall to my right side
then I'm going to go right until I get to a wall, okay?
Then if there's a wall to my right
and I can go forward I'm just going to keep going forward,
okay?
If I keep going forward and there's a wall to my right
and in front of me I'm going to turn around
and go left, okay?
And then if there's a wall to my right in front of me
and to the left then I'm going to turn around and go back.
So with this fairly simple algorithm
I just follow the path always keeping the wall to my right
and eventually I end up where I need to be, okay?
So notice I used just in plain English a few keywords, okay?
If, otherwise, things like that.
So in programming we have those same constructs
and those same sort of intuitive words
can be used to tell Python to do something
or to do something else
or to choose from a different set of possibilities, okay?
And this way we can get the computer
to make decisions for us.
And you might be thinking, well,
you said that computers can't make decisions on their own.
It's not.
US programmers are going to build these decisions
into the program and all the computer's going to do
is going to reach the decision point and say,
okay, this is a decision point.
Should I go left or should I go right?
Or which one do I pick?
And these sort of decisions are created by you as a programmer
and the computer just has to make the decision
and choose a path, okay?
So in programming there's three sort of simple ways
that you can add control flow to your programs
and that's making one decision
and choosing whether to execute something
or execute something else.
The first is the simple if, okay?
And given a program that just linearly has statements
that get executed,
whenever I reach an if statement,
you're going to check the condition.
The condition's going to be something
that's going to get evaluated to either true or false.
Okay, so I've reached the condition here.
And if the condition's true,
then I'm going to additionally execute
this extra set of expressions,
but if the condition's false,
then I'm just gonna keep going through the program
and not execute that extra set of instructions, okay?
How does Python know which instructions to execute?
They're going to be inside this,
what we call code block
and the code blocks denoted by indentation.
So it's going to be everything that's indented
is part of that if code block.
Typically four spaces indentation.
Okay, so that's how you'd write code
that decides whether to execute this extra thing or not.
Now let's say I don't just want to execute
an extra thing, I want to reach a condition,
I want to reach a point where I say,
I'll either go down this path
or I'll do something else, okay?
That's this right here.
So this if else construct says,
this is my code, I've reached my decision point here.
If the condition inside this if is true,
then I'm going to execute maybe this set of statements here.
But if the condition's not true,
then I'm not going to execute that set of statements
and instead I'm going to execute
under whatever else is.
So using this construct,
I'm either going to do one set of expressions
or the other, but never both, okay?
And after I've executed one or the other,
I'm going to continue on
with just the regular execution of the program.
All right?
Okay, so we're able to either choose one thing,
choose one thing or another,
but what if we want to have more than one choice?
So if some number is equal to zero,
I want to do this.
If it's equal to one, I want to do this.
Otherwise, if it's equal to two,
I want to do this and so on.
That's where this last one comes in.
And we introduce this other keyword here called L if.
So that stands for short form for else if.
So first we check if this condition is true.
So we're going through our program.
We've reached our decision point.
If the condition's true,
we're going to execute maybe this set of instructions.
If the condition's not true, maybe we'll check.
If the condition's not true,
we will check this next condition.
That's part of the L if right here.
And if that one's true,
we're going to execute a different set of instructions.
You can have more than one L if.
And depending on which one's true,
you're going to execute a different set of instructions.
And then this last else is sort of a catch all
where if none of the previous conditions were true,
then just do this last set of expressions.
So in this case, you're going to choose
between one of these three,
one of these four roots or however many you have.
And then when you're done making your choice,
you're going to execute the remaining set of instructions.
So the way this works is if more than one condition
is true, you're actually just going to enter one of them
and you're going to enter the very first one
that's true.
So you're never going to enter
more than one of these code blocks.
You always enter one and you enter the first one
that evaluates to true.
So notice that we denoted code blocks using indentation.
And that's actually one of the things
that I really like about Python.
It sort of forces you to write pretty code
and nice looking code and just code that's very readable.
And that enforces you to indent
everything that's a code block.
So you can easily see sort of where the flow of control is
and where decision making points are
and things like that.
So in this particular example,
we have one if statement here
and it checks if two variables are equal
and we have an if, L, if, else.
And in this example, we're going to enter
either this code block or this one or this one
depending on the variables of X and Y
and we're only going to enter one code block
and we'll enter the first one that's true.
Notice you can have nested conditionals.
So inside this first if, we have another if here
and this inner if is only going to be checked
when we enter the first, this outer if.
I do want to make one point though.
So sometimes you might forget to do the double equal side
when you check, when you're checking for equality
and that's okay.
If you just use one equal sign,
Python's going to give you an error
and it's going to say syntax error
and it's going to highlight this line
and then you're going to know that
there's a mistake there.
You should be using equality
because it doesn't make sense to be making an assignment
inside the if.
Okay, all right.
So we've learned about branching
and we know about conditionals.
Let's try to apply this to a little game
and spoiler, we won't be able to.
We'll have to learn about a new thing.
But back in 1980s, there was the Legend of Zelda
cool graphics where there was a scene with
the Lost Woods over simplification
if anyone's a Zelda die hard fan
but the basic idea was if you entered the woods
you entered from the left to the right
and then as long as you kept going right
it would show you the same screen over and over again.
And the trick was you just had to go backward
and then you'd exit the woods.
So very simple.
Using what we know so far we could sort of code this up
and we'd say something like this.
If the user exits right
then set the background to the woods background.
Otherwise set the background to the exit background.
Now let's say the user and then in the else were done.
Let's say the user went right
while you'd show them the woods background
and now ask them again where do they want to go
if they exit right,
set the background to the woods background
otherwise set the background to the exit background.
And so on.
So you notice that there's sort of no end to this, right?
How many times do you know?
Do you know how many times the user might keep going right?
They might be really persistent right?
And they'll be like maybe if I go a thousand times
I'll get out of the woods.
Or maybe a thousand and one.
Maybe.
So this would probably be who knows how deep
these nested ifs.
So we don't know.
So with what we know so far
we can't really code this cute little game.
But enter loops.
And specifically a while loop.
So this code here that could be infinitely
number of nested if statements deep
can be rewritten using these three lines.
So we say while the user exits right
set the background to the woods background
and with a while loop
it's going to do what we tell it to do inside the loop
and then it's going to check the condition again
and then it's going to do what we say
it should do inside the code block
and then it's going to check the condition again.
And then when the condition,
as long as the condition is true
it's going to keep doing that little loop there.
And as soon as the condition becomes false
it's going to stop doing the loop
and do whatever is right after the while.
So that's basically how a while loop works.
We have while, that's the keyword.
The condition is something that gets evaluated
to true or false
and once again we have a code block that's indented
and it tells Python these are the expressions I want to do
as long as the condition is true.
So the condition is true
you evaluate every expression in the code block
when you reach the end of the expression
end of the code block you check the condition again
if it's true still you keep doing the expressions
check it again and so on.
So here's a little game
and with these lines of code we were able
we can code up the last words of Zelda.
Even worse graphics by the way
than the original Zelda is this one that I coded up here.
So I print out the following things
you're in the last forest go left or right.
And my program is going to say
you're in the last forest go left or right
it's going to get user input
it's going to say while the user keeps typing in right
show them this text and ask them again.
So I'm asking them again by just saying input here again
and that's it that's going to just keep getting input
from the user and if the user doesn't type in right
and maybe types in left you're going to exit
out of this loop and print out
you got out of the last forest.
So I have to show you this
because I spent too much time on it
but I decided to improve on the code
that's in the slides
and I've written here ways that you guys can also improve it.
So if I run my code you're in the last forest
go left or right so if I say left
then yay I got out of the last forest
but if I go right then I'm stuck right.
I took down some trees
you can see there's no more trees here
I made a table and then I flipped it over.
So the expansion to this if you want to try it out
I put this in the comments here is try to use a counter.
If the user types in right the first two times
just make that a sad face
but if the user types in more than two times
make them cut down some trees and build a table and flip it.
That's a cute little expansion if you want to test yourself
to make sure you're getting loops.
Okay so so far we've used while loops
to ask for user input
and that's actually somewhere where it makes sense
to use while loops because you don't actually know
how many times the user's going to type in something.
You can use while loops to keep sort of a counter
and to write code that counts something.
If you do that though there's two things
you need to take care of.
The first is this first line here
which is sort of an initialization of this loop counter
and the second is this line here
which is incrementing your loop counter.
The reason why the second one's important
is because let's look at our condition here.
So while n is less than five.
If you didn't have this line here
you would never increment n.
So every time through the loop you'd just keep
printing zeros okay and you'd have an infinite loop.
I do want to show though what if you do have
an infinite loop it's not the end of the world.
So I can say something like so while true print zero.
So this is going to give me an infinite loop
in my program and whoop, okay.
So notice it's just printing the letter p
over and over again and if I let it go any longer
it's gonna slow down the computer.
So I'm gonna hit control C or command C maybe
and it's going to stop the program from printing okay.
So just in case you ever enter infinite loops
in your programs just go to the console
and hit control C and that's going to stop it
from sort of slowing down the computer.
Okay so going back to this example
I was saying that if you're using
counters or variables in order to sort of count up
inside the while loop you have to take care
to initialize a counter variable first
and then to increment it.
Otherwise you'll enter an infinite loop.
That feels a little bit tedious
and so there's a shortcut for doing that exact same thing.
So these four lines you can rewrite those
into these two lines right here
using this new type of loop called a for loop.
So the for loop says for some loop variable
in this case I named it n you can name it whatever you want.
In range five we're going to come back
to what range means in a little bit print n.
So every time through the loop you're going to print out
what the value of n is.
Range five actually creates internally
a sequence of numbers starting from zero
and going to that number five minus one.
So the sequence is going to be zero, one, two, three and four.
The first time through the loop you're going to say
n is equal to zero or internally this is what happens
n gets the value zero you're going to print n.
Then you're going to go back to the top
n gets the value one then you're going to go
execute whatever's inside so you're going to print one.
Then you're going to increment that
to the next value in the sequence
you're going to print out two and so on.
So this is the general look of a for loop.
So we have for some loop variable again
can be named whatever you want in range some number
do a bunch of stuff and again
these are part of this for loop code block
so you should indent them to tell Python
that these are the things that you should do.
So when you're using range some number
you start out with variable getting the value zero.
With variable having value zero
you're going to execute all of these expressions.
After all the expressions in the code block are done
you're going to go on to the next value so one.
You're going to execute all these expressions
with variable being value one and then so on and so on
until you go to sum num minus one.
So using range in that way is a little bit constraining
because you're always going to get values starting from zero
and ending at sum num minus one.
Whatever's in the parentheses in range.
Sometimes you might want to write programs
that maybe start at a custom value.
Don't start at zero maybe they start at five
maybe it started minus ten.
And sometimes you might want to write programs
that don't go with don't increment
the numbers by one but maybe skip every other number
or go every two numbers every three numbers and so on.
So you can customize range to your needs.
The one thing you do need to give it is the stop.
So if you give it only one value in the parentheses
that stands for stop.
And by default start is going to have the value zero
and step is going to have the value one.
If you give it two things in the parentheses
you're giving it start and stop.
So the first being start the second being stop
and step gets this value of one by default.
And if you give it three things in the parentheses
you're giving it start stop and step in that order.
And you're always going to start at the start value
and stop at or so you're going to start at the start value
and you're going to go until stop minus one.
So those are the sequences of numbers.
So in this first code right here
my sum is going to get the value zero
and you're going to have a for loop.
We're going to start from seven right
because we're giving it two numbers
and when you give it two numbers
it represents start and stop with step being one.
So you're starting at seven.
If step is one the next value is eight.
What's the value after that?
If we're incrementing by one nine.
And since we're going until stop minus one
we're not actually going to pick up on 10.
So this loop variable I the very first time
through the loop is going to have the value seven.
So my sum is going to be zero plus seven.
That's everything that's inside the code block.
The next time through the loop I gets the value eight.
So inside the for loop my sum gets whatever
the previous value was which was seven plus eight.
The next time through the loop my sum
gets the value seven plus eight plus nine.
Obviously replacing that with the previous value.
So 15.
Since we're not going through 10 that's where we stop
and we're going to print out my sum
which is going to be the value of seven plus eight plus nine.
Oh yeah.
Oh okay yeah.
Do they have to be integers?
That's a great question.
We can try that out.
I'm not actually sure right off just off the top of my head.
So you can go in spider and say
let's say in this example here.
In this example here.
So we can say seven point one 10.3.
Yeah so they have to be integers.
Okay so that's that's that example
and let's erase that.
In this particular example we have start stop and step
and here we're going every other value.
So we're starting at five.
Tell me what the next value is supposed to be.
If we're taking every other one.
Seven and then nine and then are we doing 11 or not?
Excellent nice yeah.
So we're going to the end minus one.
Okay so it's possible that sometimes you write code
where you might want to exit out of the loop early.
You don't want to go through all of the sequences
of your numbers.
Maybe there's a condition inside there
where you just want to exit the loop early.
Inside the Y loop maybe you want to exit the loop
before the condition becomes false.
So that's where the break statement comes in.
So the break works like this.
It's going to as soon as Python sees this break statement
it's going to say okay I'm going to look
at whatever loop I'm currently in.
I'm not evaluating any expression after it
that comes within my loop
and I'm going to immediately exit the loop.
So I'm going inside this while this while
I'm evaluating this one expression
and then I suddenly see a break.
Expression B does not get evaluated
and break is going to immediately exit
out of the innermost loop that it's in.
So this Y loop that has condition two
that's the innermost loop
that the break is found in.
So we're going to exit out of this innermost loop here
and we're evaluating expression C
and notice we're evaluating expression C
because its expression C is part of the outer Y loop.
It's at the same level as this one
and these ones are part of the inner Y loop.
Okay, last thing I want to say
is just a little bit of a comparison
between foreign Y loops.
So when would you use one or the other?
This might be useful in your problem sets.
So for loops you usually use
when you know the number of iterations.
Okay, Y loops are very useful
when for example you're getting user input
and user input is unpredictable, right?
You don't know how many times
they're gonna do a certain task.
For both foreign Y loops
you can end out of the loop early using the break.
The for loop uses this counter.
It's inherent inside the for loop.
A Y loop, you can use a counter
in order you can use a Y loop to count things
but you must initialize the counter before the Y loop
and you have to remember to increment it within the loop
otherwise you may be lead to an infinite loop.
We've seen as the very first example of a for loop
that the for loop could be rewritten as a Y loop
but the vice versa is not necessarily true.
And the counter example to that is just user input.
So you might not know how many times
you might do a certain task.
All right, great, that's all for today.